<doclite name="FScriptME">

<page name="FScriptME">

<header>
	<center><h2>_TITLE_</h2><i>by murlen</i></center>_NAVIGATE_<hr/>
</header>

<footer>
	<hr/>_NAVIGATE_<br/><i><font size="-2">created with DocLite</font></i>
</footer>

<section name="What is FScriptME?">
<p>FScriptME is an implementation of FScript designed for Java Micro Edition.
See the Sun J2ME <a href="http://java.sun.com/j2me">site</a>.
Currently FScriptME is still in beta, in that it has only recently been released
and is still relatively untested.  However it is based upon the FScript
source code and as such should be stable.</p>
<p>I am currently using FScriptME to develop a scripting environment for the 
Palm platform using <a href="http://java.sun.com/products/midp4palm/index.html">
MIDP for Palm</a>, this is still unreleased but the FScript
section was considered mature enough for independent release.</p>
</section>
<section name="How does FScriptME differ from FScript?">
<p>A number of changes were made to FScriptME to enable it to work with J2ME,
some of these changes are due to the restrictions of J2ME and some are to keep 
the code base simpler (and therefore smaller). The main changes are:
<ul>
<li>Double values are not supported</li>
<li>FScript extensions are not supported</li>
<li>The BasicIO class is not available</li>
<li>ArrayLists are replaced by Vectors in FScript methods</li>
<li>FScript's <i>run</i> method has been renamed to <i>runCode</i> so subclasses
can be made Runnable</li>
<li>Only the <i>elseif</i> keyword is supported not the optional <i>elsif</i> that is supported in fscript</li>
<li>A new keyword <i>exit</i> has been added that allows scripts to exit (somewhat like return, but terminating script execution), <i>exit</i> takes a parameter that is returned from the top level calling method (in FScript) e.g. <i>runCode</i>.  A corresponding <i>exit</i> method has been added to the <i>FScript</i> class, to allow functions implemented in subclasses to also <i>exit</i> correctly.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p>This document does <b>not</b> contain FScript information (syntax, usage etc.),
download FScript proper from the 
<a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/fscript">homepage</a> and use the 
existing FScript documentation (as FScript and FScriptME are very similar).</p>
</section>
<section name="Why GPL?">
<p>FScript was originally developed for inclusion in a commercial product, hence
the choice of the LGPL.  As FScriptME has no such restrictions I have chosen
to release it under GPL.  This does mean that FScriptME may <b>not</b> be used
as part of a commercial product. <i>However</i> I am open to relicensing on 
a product by product basis, please contact me (murlen no-spam at users dot
sourceforge dot net) if this may be of interest to you.</p>
</section>
</page>
<page name="Other Details">
<section name="Installation">
<p>Initially FScriptME is a source only release.  The source is in the
<i>murlen/util/FscriptME</i> directory.  There is no makefile or the like
provided, but basically something like <i>javac
murlen/util/fscriptME/*.class</i> would be a good start.</p>
</section>
<section name="Code size">
<p>This depends on compiler used and other factors but around 30KB would be
a typical size of a compiled FScriptME code base. By way of an example 
the MIDP for Palm application mentioned earlier is approx. 45KB</p>
</section>
<section name="Homepage">
<p>The official homepage of FScript is 
<a href="http://fscript.sourceforge.net">here</a>.</p>
<p>The SourceForge project page is 
<a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/fscript">here</a>.</p>
</section>
<section name="JavaDoc">
<p>The <a href="doc/index.html">JavaDocs</a> are in the <i>docs/doc</i>
directory.</p>
</section>
<section name="Bugs">
<p>This is beta software so bugs are to be expected.
Any bugs or feature requests can be reported to me at: <br/>
murlen (at to stop spam) users dot sourceforge dot net</p>
<p>Or via the bug tracking on 
<a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/fscript">the project home page.
</a></p> 
<p>Note that email is probably going to get a faster response, as the project
page is checked less frequently.</p>
</section>
</page>
</doclite>

